

## **Domain Proficiency**

Marketing  $\star\star\star\star\star$ Sales  $\star\star\star\star\star$ Retail  $\star\star\star\star\star$ 

# Technical Proficiency MACHINE LEARNING

Python ★★★★★ R ★★★★★ IBM SPSS Modeler ★★★★

## DATABASE MANAGEMENT & REPORTING

Sisense ★★★★

Excel ★★★★

MS SQL Server ★★★★

Teradata ★★★★

BigQuery ★★★★

#### **E2E SERVICES**

GCP ★★★★

Jenkins ★★★★

### **Related Hard Skills**

****
****
****
****
****
****

## Minakshi Aggarwal

**Data Scientist** 

minakshiagg129@gmail.com | +91–9962-97-9196 LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/minakshi-aggarwal-bb44523b> Bangalore

## **Summary**

My near 5 years of experience as a data scientist covered most machine learning techniques used in predictive modeling, while intuitively building prescriptions that are well aligned to the client's requirement and easily understood without confounding them with the intricacies. I am good at stats, breaking high level problems to align them with analytical solutions and a great learner, constantly seeking out challenging avenues to build my skills while helping the organization to realize higher ROI.

## **Work Experience**

#### **ASCENA RETAIL GROUP**

DATA SCIENTIST Sept 2018 – Present

• In-House Solutions to Various Projects

- Migrated various projects from Legacy Third Party environments to deployment over GCP (in-house) solutions, for multiple brands
- 2. Annual savings of around 0.75 million dollars per year in terms of eliminating contracted third party infrastructure/workflows
- Multiple Customer Campaign Varieties
  - Implemented multiple campaigns ranging from promotional, upselling, cross-selling, churn, holiday etc. that has had varied benefits in terms of the uplift margins
  - 2. For the plus segment, the uplift margin was around 1 dollar per customer

#### FRESHWORKS INC.

**DATA ANALYST** 

Mar 2018 - Aug 2018

FreshChat

Fixed major issues on the chat infrastructure by performing RCA on the logs

- E2E multiple dashboard covering from Sales to Rol
  - Implemented data connectivity between various CRM tools and designed the front-end for each dashboard for tracking from Pre-Sales to Rol
  - 2. Helped reduce the man hours effort from sales team, due to tracking, by 1 hour per day for each sales person

#### **VERIZON DATA SERVICES PVT LTD.**

ANALYST (DATA SCIENTIST)

Apr 2016 – Mar 2018

- Sales Funnel Analytics (Pre Sales) Team Lead / Agile Team Facilitator
  - 1. Predicted the quarterly sales disposition with an accuracy of 85%.
  - 2. Improved the revenue from new customers by 11% in 2017.
- Analysis on Broken Promise (Post Sales) Project Owner
   Developed a classification model which helped reduce the number of monthly broken promises from an average of 25% to 12%.

#### **Soft Skills**

### **Achievements**

#### **ASCENA**

Internal Recognition for successful migration of contracted jobs to in-house solutions.

#### **VERIZON**

Received 3 Spotlight Awards –

- 'Payment Investigation' module
- Spring Hackathon 2015
- Data Science trainings

#### **OTHERS**

Ranked in the top 5% in the McKinsey Hackathon based on the AUC index.

#### Organizational Training on Data Science (Trainings)

Trained 10% of workforce under the Enterprise vertical to be analytically driven and data science ready.

Analytics Dev Ops Environment (Infrastructure)

Implemented a robust delivery process for Data Science projects that reduced deploying and maintaining efforts by 10-man hours per week.

#### **VERIZON DATA SERVICES PVT LTD.**

**SOFTWARE ENGINEER (DATA SCIENTIST)** 

Jun 2014 - Apr 2016

Customer Market Segment Analysis (Pre Sales)

Clustered new logos by marketing segment, bringing in 17% more revenue in Q2 2015.

• Billing Tickets Bucketing Analysis (Post Sales)

Classified inbound billing tickets automatically, reducing manual effort by nearly 90%.

Upsell/Cross-Sell opportunities (Pre Sales)

Hackathon winning statistical model that buffed our sales over 8% by identifying and generating additional 15% leads for upsell and cross-sell.

#### INDIAN INSTITUTE OF REMOTE SENSING

**INTERNSHIP** 

May 2013 - Jun 2013

- Completed training on embedded systems and the 8051 micro-controllers.
- Implemented a program that stitched images to create 3d models using k means clustering.

#### **Education**

National Institute of Technology, Hamirpur Aug 2010 Bachelor of Technology in Electronics & Communications Engineering

Aug 2010 - May 2014